Guide to the Interviews by Kathryn M. Moore, 1975-1976.
Interviews by Kathryn M. Moore, 1975-1976
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Interviews by Kathryn M. Moore, 1975-1976.
21-32-2360
Kathryn M. Moore.
19 cassette tapes.
Cassette tapes and transcripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Interviews with fifteen Cornell emeritus women professors and notable women conducted by Kathryn M. Moore. Interviewees include Cornell professors Alice Bryant, Helen Dudley Bull, Ruth Comstock, Alice Cook, Louise Daniel, Eleanor Emerson, Eleanor Gibson, Isabel Peard, Mabel Rollins, Laura Lee Smith, Evelyn Stout, and Ethel Vatter. Other notable women interviewed are Constance Cook, Katherine Palmer, and Bernice Sandler.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Interviews with fifteen Cornell emeritus women professors and notable women conducted by Kathryn M. Moore. Interviewees include Cornell professors Alice Bryant, Helen Dudley Bull, Ruth Comstock, Alice Cook, Louise Daniel, Eleanor Emerson, Eleanor Gibson, Isabel Peard, Mabel Rollins, Laura Lee Smith, Evelyn Stout, and Ethel Vatter. Other notable women interviewed are Constance Cook, Katherine Palmer, and Bernice Sandler.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Moore, Kathryn M.; Blackwell, Sally.; Bryant, Alice.; Bull, Helen Dudley.; Comstock, Ruth B.; Cook, Alice Hanson.; Cook, Constance Eberhardt.; Daniel, Louise Jane, 1912-; Emerson, Eleanor, 1777-1808; Gallup, Jane.; Gibson, Eleanor Jack.; Kittrell, Flemmie P. (Flemmie Pansy), 1904-1980; Palmer, Katherine V. W. (Katherine Van Winkle), 1895-; Peard, Isabel J.; Proud, Dorothy.; Rollins, Mabel, 1909-; Sandler, Bernice Resnick.; Smith, Laura Lee.; Stout, Evelyn E.; Vatter, Ethel G.; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
Women college teachers.; Women--Education--New York (State); Women--Education (Higher)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Alice Bryant, Food Sciences, Apr. 15, 1976; tr. 5291a
- Helen Dudley Bull, MD, Family Studies, tr. 5292a
- Ruth Comstock, Home Ec Extension, Housing and Design, tr. 5293a
- Alice Cook (2), ILR (of special value), Mar. 27, 1975; tr. 5294a, 5295a
- Connie Cook, Cornell alumna, lawyer, and former New York State Assemblywoman (Ithaca), Apr. 9, 1975 (?); tr. 5296a
- Louise Daniel, Biochemistry/Nutrition, June 2, 1975; tr. 5297a
- Eleanor Emerson (2), ILR (of special value), Apr. 26, 1975 (?); tr. 5298a, 5299a
- Eleanor Gibson, Psychology (of special value), tr. 5300a
- Katherine Palmer, Paleontological Research Institution (of special value), tr. 5301a
- Isabel Peard, Education - Student personal work, May 6, 1975; tr. 5302a
- Mabel Rollins (2), Consumer Economics (of special value), Apr. 21, 1976; tr. 5303a, 5304a
- Bernice Sandler, "Women and the Law" (broken?), Apr. 9, 1975; tr. 5305a
- Laura Lee Smith, Food Chemistry (of special value), Apr. 24, 1975; tr. 5306a, 5307a
- Evelyn Stout, Textiles, Apr. 20, 1976; tr. 5308a
- Ethel Vatter, Family Economics (of special value), tr. 5309a
- Interview Questions and Forms, etc. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Roselle Oyer's "Study on Female Faculty Members at Cornell University", January 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Sally Blackwell (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Helen Dudley Bull (Box 1, Folder 4)
- E.V. Colbert (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Interview with Eleanor J. Gibson by Margaret Savino, May 9, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Flemmie Kitrell (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Katherine Van Winkle Palmer (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Isabel Peard (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Dorothy Proud (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mabel Rollins, April 21, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Evelyn Stout (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Oral History (Box 1, Folder 13)